It's called a "gas weapon."
The gas was made with
some of my spinal fluid.
Inhaling even a small amount
makes any Subjects of Ymir freeze up,
lose control of their bodies,
and then fall unconscious.
This also etches
a coordinate inside them.
I use this path to send
the Power of the Titans
to said coordinate.
And that's why the people of that village
transformed into obedient Titans.
It was called "Ragako."
Not "that village."
And seeing as you murdered
every person who lived there,
you should learn the name,
you bearded shit.
Look. It's not like
I wanted to do it.
I just did what was needed
to convince the Marleyans
that I was loyal to them.
If they'd learned the truth,
I never could've brought
hope to this island.
None of this is new to you, though.
I told you guys the exact same
thing when I first got here.
Why do you keep asking me about it?
Because I can see that
you aren't burdened
by a shred of guilt
over what you've done.
I still can't tell if you
actually wanna save Eldia,
but it's clear that those lives
meant nothing to you.
Doubt you were well-liked by the ladies.
Considering how you think you know
what everyone else is feeling.
I do know. And I
was liked enough. So...
Well good for you!
Anyway, when are you
gonna let me meet with Eren
so we can run our experiment?
That isn't my call to make.
We're waiting for HQ.
If your commanders think
that they have time to spare,
then they couldn't be more wrong.
On that one point, we agree.
Captain Levi!
What? Are you serious?
This building's so big!
I've never seen anything like it!
Neither have I!
It must be your lucky day.
Y'all ready for some fancy dinin'?
Yeah!
What's the matter, Mia?
You got the jitters?
Uh. No, I'm fine. Thanks.
All this fancy stuff make you nervous?
I knew you were country kids,
but I didn't know it was this bad.
No. I... Kaya.
Is there actually
a Marleyan prisoner of war
working at this place?
Yeah, he's here for sure, so get a grip.
And watch out 'cause
soldiers eat here, too.
Even if this prisoner
can't help us get out,
he'll be good to know.
Mr. Braus! I'm glad that
you were able to come.
So am I. Thanks for
the invitation.
Wow. Look at all these kids.
You brought quite the crowd with you.
Figured I might as well
bring the whole family.
You did say it was "on the
house." Right, Nicolo?
Yes. All of you are
welcome here.
Come. This way.
I'm really hungry, dad!
That chef named Nicolo is the
Marleyan who invited us here.
See if he can help you.
Why was someone like Mr. Braus
invited to eat here anyway?
I mean he's not a soldier.
The Braus's eldest was the girl
who saved me from a Titan.
They met Nicolo at her grave,
and got to talking.
She loved his cooking,
so he offered to treat them
to the meal he'll never get to make her.
He didn't say this, but personally,
I think they were in love.
Ben? What's the matter?
You got a stomach bug or somethin'?
No. I'm fine.
Delicious! I've never had a meal
this good in my whole life!
Well, if you like that,
then just wait till
you get to the main dish!
Nicolo, you've got more guests.
Huh? Who's here at this hour?
The Scout Regiment.
Hello there. This urgent?
Sorry, but...
I'm preparing a main course for
some very important guests right now.
That's fine. If you're
in the middle of something,
you can get back to it.
But, we'd like to have
a quick word with you
once you finish up.
You wanna talk?
What is this about?
We wondered if you might
have some concerns.
The scouts're investigating
our detainment.
We were hoping you'd be able to help us.
Yeah. No problem.
I'll ask you to wait in
here until I can finish.
Wow. This room is pretty fancy.
I bet it's usually reserved for MPs.
Hey. I've heard
a whole lotta talk
about this wine. It's so
nice that it's only served
to high-ranking members of the military.
Oh yeah?
Well, aren't we high-ranking
members of the Scouts?
Sure are!
I'd say we've earned
a quick sip of liquid luxury.
Let's have a little...
Don't touch that!
Whoa, calm down, man.
We were just screwing around, so relax.
No need to make a big thing of it.
A wine of this quality would be
wasted on Eldians, understand?
- -What?
- -What's with you?
I can't believe you're
still spouting that crap.
Regardless of what you've been told,
your wine doesn't care what race we are!
Get your hands off me, Eldian.
I've been civil to you, but that
doesn't make us friends.
It sounds to me like you've
forgotten your place here.
On this island, you're just...
Just a filthy POW?
Guess that makes us even,
you Eldian devil.
What is that guy's problem?
Hell if I know. Whatever!
'Kay. Now. Go for it!
My stomach hurts real bad!
Is there some way we can help?
Don't tell me it's
'cause of something you ate.
I should be okay, but I'm
gonna go to the restroom.
I'll go with him.
Just in case something goes
wrong while he's in there.
Good luck.
Hey, uh. The restroom
is the other way.
That's not what we're here for, Nicolo.
We're warrior candidates from Marley.
And we're in hiding right now.
Huh?
We have reason to
believe that this island
is about to be invaded by
an allied army made up of
every major country in the world.
Until that army comes,
just hang in there!
And also, spread the word
to any other Marleyan
captives you know!
Wait. Take it back a few steps.
How'd a pair of Warrior
Candidates like you
even get here?
These island devils raided
Liberio about a month ago.
This might be hard to believe,
but we actually fought
our way onto the airship
they used to retreat
and got taken prisoner.
Did you kill anyone?
A female... soldier?
Yeah. I brought her down!
I've only rid the world of
a few devils so far.
But I give you my word.
Our real revenge hasn't even started yet!
Help's coming. And when
the army gets here...
Hey. Stop!
What is it?
It was you. You killed her.
You're the little wretch
who murdered Sasha!
Falco? Hey. Falco!
Falco. Are you okay?
Falco. Falco!
Get up! Hey! Wake up!
Shit. Shit!
Falco!
Wha... Nicolo! What're you
doin' to Ben and Mia?
"Mia" here's been
keeping secrets from you.
One being that she was
the one who murdered Sasha.
She may be a kid,
but she's also a trained
Marleyan soldier.
She climbed aboard the Scout's
airship as it left Marley
and shot Sasha in cold blood.
She's the reason your daughter's gone.
Your daughter?
Take it, Mr. Braus. Go ahead.
If you can't bring yourself to kill her,
then I can do it for you.
As the father, it's your call.
Wha... What's going on in here?
Everybody hurry over!
Huh? What is it?
That's the kid who shot Sasha!
I heard she was on the run,
but I'm surprised you recognized her.
Wait, what are you planning to do here?
Stay away from me! You hear?
I'm just going to avenge Sasha.
That's all I want!
Stop. Leave Falco
out of this, please!
What, is this brat
someone special to you?
Is that why he tried
to protect you earlier?
You care about him, huh?
Well, I used to care about someone, too!
A dirt-blooded Eldian!
A descendant of devils!
A woman who enjoyed the food I cooked
more than anyone I'd ever met before!
She saved me from this
shitty-ass, pointless war!
She showed me that
the person I'm meant to be
is a man who brings people
happiness through his cooking.
Her name was Sasha Braus.
She was amazing.
And you stole her from me!
I've lost people, too.
Your Sasha Braus
shot two friends of mine!
She gunned them both down as
they were protecting their home!
That's why I took revenge on her!
She's the one who started it!
Shut the hell up!
Who cares how it started?
Wake up! Open your eyes!
You're supposed to be a Marleyan soldier!
That she-devil must've
bewitched you somehow.
Fight! Don't let the devils win!
All right, Nicolo.
Gimme that knife.
Please.
Listen, Mr. Braus.
This isn't right.
Please drop the knife.
Or maybe just set it down.
I raised Sasha to be self-sufficient.
Uh. What?
I taught her how to use a bow
when she was young,
and before long, she got good enough
to hunt for food in our forest.
It was our way of life, and we
didn't ever wanna give it up.
But after Maria fell, I knew we'd have to
change with the times
or die with the old ways,
so I sent Sasha to join civilization.
Then, the world just kept gettin' bigger.
Sasha left our forest
and our island behind,
to fight some distant enemy.
To shoot folks and get shot.
Thing is. She left our forest,
but it turns out she just
traded it for a bigger one,
where the same rule of "kill
or be killed" still applied.
I reckon Sasha died
'cause she wandered in
that forest for too long.
We've gotta get the children
outta that forest
at the very least.
Or else there's nothing gonna stop this
from happenin' again and again.
Way I see it,
when it comes to shouldering the
sins and hatreds of the past,
that burden should fall to
adults like you and me.
Please, Nicolo. We need
you to let Ben go now.
Good. Okay.
Slow and steady does it, Lisa.
Right.
Show me your wounds.
Mia. You're okay, aren't you?
I-I don't understand.
Do you really not hate me?
Kaya...
Kaya stop, calm down, please.
Murderer! You killed my sister!
How dare you say my name!
I thought you were
my friend! How could you?!
I think we should go. Come on.
The main dish must've gone cold by now.
Hange. You should rinse out
that kid's mouth out with water.
Some of the wine got into it.
Huh?
Although...
It's probably too late.
Why do you say that?
What's in the wine?
I think... it's
Zeke's spinal fluid.
Zachary was assassinated?
That's correct.
The Jaegerists effectively
control everything inside the walls now.
We believe that all this chaos
is being caused by Zeke,
through a plan that he's been
using Eren and Yelena to implement.
What now?
Not sure, but the way
the winds are blowing right now,
I think Eren will be
brought to Zeke soon,
just as the Jaegerists
have been demanding.
What about Pyxis?
He's just rolling over?
He remains steadfast.
He plans to make his move
while Eren's being led here.
And this plan involves
having somebody eat Eren, right?
We're gonna kill him ourselves.
That's right.
Tch.
I've saved Eren, again and again,
watching more of my
comrades die every time.
I did that because I believed
he was the best hope humanity had.
And this.
This is where that belief has gotten me.
It's like I'm at the punchline
of some awful joke.
What the hell became of
the hope we all looked towards?
All that struggle.
All that death.
For this farce.
Such bullshit.
It's not even funny.
The piece of shit
we need to feed to a Titan
is right beneath us.
What did you just say?
Why the hell would Zeke Jaeger's
spinal fluid be in the wine?
I don't actually
have proof. But still.
They packed the first survey
fleet to the brim with it.
There's no way they'd've needed
that much alcohol for a scouting mission.
Again.
And. Just as I was
starting to settle into
my new job here as a chef,
I received instructions.
In short, I was ordered to start
serving that Marleyan wine
to high-ranking military officers.
Who ordered it?
It was Yelena.
As far as I know, she's the
only one who was in on it.
I can't speak for the other volunteers.
No. I... I didn't know
about any of this.
I give you my word.
This doesn't make sense though!
When Zeke's spinal fluid
is ingested by an Eldian,
they're supposed to freeze up.
That's only what we were told by Zeke.
None of us have ever seen
how it happens in person.
And there was no proof.
But we bought it.
It seems like such a small lie,
but it's had an enormous effect.
We thought Zeke's spinal
fluid caused paralysis,
so when the wine caused no symptoms,
we assumed it was safe.
Yeah, but wait. Nicolo.
You don't actually know
that it's dosed, right?
No. Not for a fact.
That said, I do know that in the past,
Zeke's spinal fluid has been
used in similar ways,
to tremendous effect.
Ten years ago, Marley conquered
a hostile nation's capital overnight.
This was made possible
by the sudden appearance
of hundreds of Titans in the city.
She must plan to use the same trick here.
Why else would she
order me to make sure that
your military's top officers
drank that suspicious wine?
No other explanation makes sense.
If that's true, then when you snatched
that bottle from me earlier,
you were trying to protect us.
No. I have no idea
what I'm doing.
I came here to help save the world
from the devils on this island.
Now that I've told you all of this,
I'm sure that my days must be numbered.
Sorry, Mr. Braus.
I can't be as forgiving as you are,
but I do want to atone in some small way.
I was about to murder a child.
How screwed up can I be?
I... I just... I...
Oh, Nicolo.
Tell me. Why did you save me?
Don't know. Guess I really
didn't have a reason.
I'm the one who killed
your comrades on that airship.
I'm the one who crushed that
guard's skull with a brick.
Falco didn't do anything.
So kill me, not him. Okay?
We won't kill you.
Why not?
I know you must want to.
Why would I want that?
Always with the killing.
It's like it's all you ever think about.
Just like someone else I know.
Er...
Is something wrong?
There you are, Commander.
What's going on?
I'm glad you showed up.
If anyone knows where
Zeke's being held, it's you.
You'll have to drop
whatever it is you're doing
and take us to him.
Wait. We have no intention
of fighting you.
Didn't you get the military's proposal?
We did, and we promptly rejected it.
We refuse to negotiate
with your military.
I see. And why is that?
The decision came from Eren.
He knew that Commander
Pyxis would never leave
the fate of the island
in our hands willingly.
And I agree.
I'm sure that Pyxis is
frantically devising a plan
to ambush Eren and steal the
Founder, even as we speak.
You have quite the imagination.
Or did this come from one of your sources
in the Garrison Regiment?
You have comrades
undercover there, don't you?
Do I look like one of your eager lackeys
who's gonna answer
any question that you ask?
Get moving.
I'm willing to prove that
I don't answer to you,
if it comes down to it,
but I'm hoping that you'll
just come along quietly.
Damn it.
How the hell did they know
to look for us here?
Greiz?
Don't tell me you brought them.
Did Yelena put you up to this?
Nicolo.
You've become far too attached
to this group of Eldians.
I knew that you and I would
stand opposed eventually.
I was right not to tell you how to
contact the Scouts when you asked.
Floch, listen!
We can't afford to waste time
fighting amongst ourselves right now!
Wine that's been tainted
with Zeke's spinal fluid
has been disseminated
throughout the military!
Zeke has us dancing
in the palm of his hand!
We have to stop him!
Actually, we don't.
Sounds like those idiot MPs are
gonna become even bigger idiots.
Now let's get moving.
I never said that the MPs drank it.
You're kidding. You knew?
You let them drink that poison?
Keep it down, will ya?
This is a family restaurant.
We're gonna go on ahead.
Good.
That was Floch.
So you brought him here with you, then?
Yeah.
I wanted to talk with you two.
As his supporters take Hange
and the others captive,
Eren stares intensely
at Armin and Mikasa.
He wants to talk.
Next episode: "Savagery."